var quiz1 = {
    "JS": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "The expenditure on the project _____ as follows: equipment Rs.20 lakhs, salaries Rs.12  lakhs, and contingency Rs.3 lakhs. Inside which HTML element do we put the JavaScript?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "break down",
                    "b": "break",
                    "c": "breaks down ",
                    "d": "breaks",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "breaks down",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "The search engine’s business model ___________ around the fulcrum of trust.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "revolves ",
                    "b": "plays",
                    "c": "sinks",
                    "d": "bursts",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "revolves ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "Two cars start at the same time from the same location and go in the same direction. The speed of the first car is 50 km/h and the speed of the second car is 60 km/h. The number of  hours it takes for the distance between the two cars to be 20 km is ___. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1",
                    "b": "2",
                    "c": "3",
                    "d": "6",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "2 ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "Ten friends  planned to share equally the cost of buying a gift for their teacher.When two of  them decided not to contribute, each of the other friends had to pay Rs 150 more. The cost of the gift was Rs. ____. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "666",
                    "b": "3000 ",
                    "c": "6000 ",
                    "d": "12000 ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "6000",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "A court is to a judge as _____________ is to a teacher",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "a student ",
                    "b": " a punishment",
                    "c": "a syllabus ",
                    "d": "a school",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "a school",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "The police arrested four criminals – P, Q, R and S. The criminals knew each other. They made the following statements: \n P says “Q committed the crime.” \n Q says “S committed the crime.” \n R says “I did not do it.” \n S says “What Q said about me is false.” \nAssume only one of the arrested four committed the crime and only one of the statements made above is true. Who committed the crime? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "P",
                    "b": "R",
                    "c": "S",
                    "d": "Q",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "R",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "'A recent High Court judgement has sought to dispel the idea of begging as a disease  — which leads to its stigmatization and criminalization — and to regard it as a symptom. The underlying disease is the failure of the state to protect citizens who fall through the social security net.'\n Which one of the following statements can be inferred from the given passage? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Beggars are lazy people who beg because they are unwilling to work ",
                    "b": "Beggars are created because of the lack of social welfare schemes ",
                    "c": "Begging is an offence that has to be dealt with firmly ",
                    "d": " Begging has to be banned because it adversely affects the welfare of the state",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Beggars are created because of the lack of social welfare schemes ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": " In a college, there are three student clubs. Sixty students are only in the Drama club, 80 students are only in the Dance club, 30 students are only in the Maths club, 40 students  are in both Drama and Dance clubs, 12 students are in both Dance and Maths clubs, 7 students are in both Drama and Maths clubs, and 2 students are in all the clubs. If 75%  of the students in the college are not in any of these clubs, then the total number of students in the college is _____.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1000",
                    "b": "975",
                    "c": "900",
                    "d": "225",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "900",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "A certain processor uses a fully associative cache of size 16 kB. The cache block size is 16  bytes. Assume that the main memory is byte addressable and uses a 32-bit address. How  many bits are required for the Tag and the Index fields respectively in the addresses generated by the processor?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " 24 bits and 0 bits",
                    "b": " 28 bits and 4 bits ",
                    "c": " 24 bits and 4 bits ",
                    "d": " 28 bits and 0 bits ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": " 28 bits and 0 bits ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "Which one of the following kinds of derivation is used by LR parsers?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Leftmost ",
                    "b": "Leftmost in reverse",
                    "c": "Rightmost  ",
                    "d": "Rightmost in reverse ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Rightmost in reverse ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "4 In 16-bit 2’s complement representation, the decimal number −28 is: ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " 1111 1111 0001 1100 ",
                    "b": " 0000 0000 1110 0100 ",
                    "c": " 1111 1111 1110 0100 ",
                    "d": " 1000 0000 1110 0100",
                }
            ],
            "answer": " 1000 0000 1110 0100",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Which one of the following is NOT a valid identity? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "  (x - y)  z = x (y - z) ",
                    "b": " (x + y) z = x (y + z) ",
                    "c": "  x - y = x + y, if xy = 0 ",
                    "d": "  x + y = (xy + x′y′)′ ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": " (x + y) z = x (y + z) ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "Consider  Z = X – Y, where X, Y and Z are all in sign-magnitude form. X and Y are each represented in bits. To avoid overflow, the representation of Z would require a minimum of:",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "  2 bits",
                    "b": "  1 bits ",
                    "c": "  3 bits ",
                    "d": "  4 bits",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "  3 bits",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": " Let  be a square matrix. Consider the following two statements on .\n    I. is invertible.\n    II. Determinant of is non-zero.\nWhich one of the following is TRUE? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "  I implies II; II does not imply I.",
                    "b": "  II implies I; I does not imply II.  ",
                    "c": "  I does not imply II; II does not imply I.",
                    "d": "  I and II are equivalent statements. ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "  I and II are equivalent statements.",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Let be an arbitrary group. Consider the following relations on : \n1: ∀1−1 \n2: ∀2−1 \n Which of the above is/are equivalence relation/relations? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " 1 and 2 ",
                    "b": " 1 only ",
                    "c": " 2 only  ",
                    "d": " Neither 1 nor 2",
                }
            ],
            "answer": " 1 only",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Consider the following two statements about database transaction schedules: \nI.Strict two-phase locking protocol generates conflict serializable schedules that are also recoverable. \nII.Timestamp-ordering concurrency control protocol with Thomas’ Write Rule can generate view serializable schedules that are not conflict serializable.\n Which of the above statements is/are TRUE?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " I only  ",
                    "b": " II only",
                    "c": " Both I and II ",
                    "d": " Neither I nor II ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Both I and II",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": " Let be an undirected complete graph on vertices, where . Then, the number of different Hamiltonian cycles in is equal to",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "n! ",
                    "b": " (n-1)!",
                    "c": "1",
                    "d": "(n-1)!/2",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "1 or (n-1)!/2",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "Which one of the following statements is NOT correct about the B+ tree data structure used for creating an index of a relational database table?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "B+ Tree is a height-balanced tree ",
                    "b": "Non-leaf nodes have pointers to data records",
                    "c": "Key values in each node are kept in sorted order",
                    "d": "Each leaf node has a pointer to the next leaf node",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Non-leaf nodes have pointers to data records",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "Which of the following protocol pairs can be used to send and retrieve e-mails (in that order)? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "IMAP, POP3 ",
                    "b": "SMTP, MIME",
                    "c": "SMTP, POP3 ",
                    "d": "IMAP, SMTP",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "SMTP, POP3 ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "The following C program is executed on a Unix/Linux system: \n    #include <unistd.h> \n   int main() \n   { \n   int i; \n   for (i=0; i<10; i++) \n   if (i%2 == 0) fork(); \n   return 0; \n   } \nThe total number of child processes created is ________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "31 to 30",
                    "b": "31 to 31",
                    "c": "0 to 31 ",
                    "d": "0 to 30",
                }
            ],
            "answer": " 31 to 31",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 21,
            "question": "Consider the following C program: \n    #include <stdio.h> \n    int jumble(int x, int y){ \n    x=2*x+y; \n    return x; \n    } \n    int main(){ \n    int x=2, y=5; \n    y=jumble(y,x); \n    x=jumble(y,x); \n    printf(“%d \n”, x); \n    return 0; \n    } \nThe value printed by the program is ________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "26 to 26",
                    "b": "31 to 31",
                    "c": "30 to 30 ",
                    "d": "32 to 32",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "26 to 26",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 22,
            "question": "20 An array of 25 distinct elements is to be sorted using quicksort. Assume that the pivot element is chosen uniformly at random. The probability that the pivot element gets placed in the worst possible location in the first round of partitioning (rounded off to 2 decimal places) is ________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "0.08 to 0.08 ",
                    "b": "0.07 to 0.07",
                    "c": "0.06 to 0.06 ",
                    "d": "0.09 to 0.09",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "0.08 to 0.08",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 23,
            "question": "A court is to a judge as _____________ is to a teacher",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "a student ",
                    "b": " a punishment",
                    "c": "a syllabus ",
                    "d": "a school",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "a school",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 24,
            "question": "The value of 3 51 mod 5 is ________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "6 to 6",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "2 to 2",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 25,
            "question": " Two numbers are chosen independently and uniformly at random from the set {1,2 , . . . , 13}. The probability (rounded off to 3 decimal places) that their 4-bit (unsigned) binary representations have the same most significant bit is ___________",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " 0.499 to 0.500",
                    "b": " 0.502 to 0.502",
                    "c": " 0.502 to 0.504",
                    "d": " 1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "0.502 to 0.504",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 26,
            "question": "Consider the following C program: \n    #include <stdio.h> \n    int main(){ \n    int arr[]={1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,0,1,2,5}, *ip=arr+4; \n    printf(“%d\n”, ip[1]); \n    return 0; \n    } \n The number that will be displayed on execution of the program is ___________ .",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "6 to 6",
                    "b": "1 to 1",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "3 to 3",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "6 to 6",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 27,
            "question": "I Consider the following C function.\n    void convert(int n){ \n    if(n<0) \n    printf(“%d”,n); \n    else { \n    convert(n/2); \n    printf(“%d”,n%2); \n    } \n   } \n Which one of the following will happen when the function convert is called with any positive integer n as argument?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "It will print the binary representation of n and terminate ",
                    "b": "It will print the binary representation of n in the reverse order and terminate",
                    "c": "It will print the binary representation of n but will not terminate ",
                    "d": "It will not print anything and will not terminate",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "It will not print anything and will not terminate",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 28,
            "question": "Consider the following C program: \n    #include <stdio.h> \n    int r(){ \n    static int num=7; \n    return num--; \n    } \n    int main(){ \n    for (r();r();r()) \n    printf(“%d”,r()); \n    return 0; \n    } \nWhich one of the following values will be displayed on execution of the programs?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "41",
                    "b": "52",
                    "c": "63",
                    "d": "630",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "52",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 29,
            "question": "Consider three machines M, N, and P with IP addresses 100.10.5.2, 100.10.5.5, and 100.10.5.6 respectively. The subnet mask is set to 255.255.255.252 for all the three  machines. Which one of the following is true? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " M, N, and P all belong to the same subnet",
                    "b": " Only M and N belong to the same subnet",
                    "c": " Only N and P belong to the same subnet ",
                    "d": " M, N, and P belong to three different subnets",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Only N and P belong to the same subnet ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 30,
            "question": "Suppose that in an IP-over-Ethernet network, a machine X wishes to find the MAC address of another machine Y in its subnet. Which one of the following techniques can be used for this?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " X sends an ARP request packet to the local gateway’s IP address which then finds the MAC address of Y and sends to X",
                    "b": " X sends an ARP request packet to the local gateway’s MAC address which then finds the MAC address of Y and sends to X ",
                    "c": " X sends an ARP request packet with broadcast MAC address in its local subnet",
                    "d": " X sends an ARP request packet with broadcast IP address in its local subnet",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "X sends an ARP request packet with broadcast MAC address in its local subnet ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 31,
            "question": "Let the set of functional dependencies F = {QR → S, R → P, S → Q} hold on a relation schema X = (PQRS). X is not in BCNF. Suppose X is decomposed into two schemas Y and  Z, where Y = (PR) and Z = (QRS). \nConsider the two statements given below.\n    I. Both Y and Z are in BCNF \n    II. Decomposition of X into Y and Z is dependency preserving and lossless \nWhich of the above statements is/are correct?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Both I and II ",
                    "b": "I only t",
                    "c": "II only ",
                    "d": "Neither I nor II ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "II only",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 32,
            "question": "Assume that in a certain computer, the virtual addresses are 64 bits long and the physical addresses are 48 bits long. The memory is word addressible. The page size is 8 kB and the word size is 4 bytes. The Translation Look-aside Buffer (TLB) in the address translation path has 128 valid entries. At most how many distinct virtual addresses can be translated without any TLB miss? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " 16×2^10",
                    "b": " 256×2^10",
                    "c": " 4×2^20",
                    "d": " 8×2^20",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "256×2^10",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 33,
            "question": " Consider the following sets: \n   S1. Set of all recursively enumerable languages over the alphabet {0,1} \n   S2. Set of all syntactically valid C programs \n   S3. Set of all languages over the alphabet {0,1} \n   S4. Set of all non-regular languages over the alphabet {0,1} \n Which of the above sets are uncountable?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "S1 and S2 ",
                    "b": "S3 and S4 ",
                    "c": " S2 and S4 ",
                    "d": " S1 and S4 ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": " S3 and S4 ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 34,
            "question": " There are n unsorted arrays: A1, A2, …, An. Assume that n is odd. Each of A1, A2, …, An contains n distinct elements. There are no common elements between any two arrays. The worst-case time complexity of computing the median of the medians of A1, A2, …, An  is ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "O(n) ",
                    "b": "O(n log n) ",
                    "c": "O(n2 ) ",
                    "d": "Ω(n2 log n)",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "O(n2 )",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 35,
            "question": " Let be any connected, weighted, undirected graph. \n   I. has a unique minimum spanning tree, if no two edges of have the same weight. \n   II. has a unique minimum spanning tree, if, for every cut of , there is a unique \nminimum-weight edge crossing the cut.Which of the above two statements is/are TRUE?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "I only ",
                    "b": "II onlyt",
                    "c": "Both I and II",
                    "d": " Neither I nor II",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Both I and II",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 36,
            "question": "The value of 3 51 mod 5 is ________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "6 to 6",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "2 to 2",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 37,
            "question": "Consider the following statements: \n   I. The smallest element in a max-heap is always at a leaf node \n   II. The second largest element in a max-heap is always a child of the root node \n   III. A max-heap can be constructed from a binary search tree in Θ(time \n   IV. A binary search tree can be constructed from a max-heap in Θ time \nWhich of the above statements are TRUE? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "I, II and III",
                    "b": "I, II and IV",
                    "c": "I, III and IV",
                    "d": "II, II and IV",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "I, II and III",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 38,
            "question": "The index node (inode) of a Unix-like file system has 12 direct, one single-indirect and one double-indirect pointers. The disk block size is 4 kB, and the disk block address is 32-bits long. The maximum possible file size is (rounded off to 1 decimal place) _________ GB. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "3.7 to 3.8",
                    "b": " 4.4 to 4.7",
                    "c": "3.06 to 3.06",
                    "d": "3.05 to 4.55",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "3.7 to 3.8",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 39,
            "question": " Consider the augmented grammar given below: \nS' → S \nS → 〈L〉 | id \nL → L,S | S \nLet I0 = CLOSURE ({[S' → •S]}). The number of items in the set GOTO (I0 , 〈 ) is: ________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "5 to 5",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "5 to 5",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 40,
            "question": "A certain processor deploys a single-level cache. The cache block size is 8 words and the word size is 4 bytes. The memory system uses a 60-MHz clock. To service a cache miss, the  memory controller first takes 1 cycle to accept the starting address of the block, it then takes 3 cycles to fetch all the eight words of the block, and finally transmits the words of the requested block at the rate of 1 word per cycle. The maximum bandwidth for the memory system when the program running on the processor issues a series of read operations is __________× 106 bytes/sec. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "155 to 155",
                    "b": "250 to 250",
                    "c": "160 to 160",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "160 to 160",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 41,
            "question": "Let be a full binary tree with 8 leaves. (A full binary tree has every level full.) Suppose two leaves and of chosen uniformly and independently at random. The expected value of  the distance between and in (i.e., the number of edges in the unique path between and ) is (rounded off to 2 decimal places) ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "2.58 to 2.58",
                    "b": "4.25 to 4.25",
                    "c": "4.55 to 4.55",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "4.25 to 4.25",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 42,
            "question": "Suppose is distributed uniformly in the open interval (1,6). The probability that the polynomial 32 + 6has only real roots is (rounded off to 1 decimal place)  ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "0.6 to 0.6",
                    "b": "0.8 to 0.8",
                    "c": "0.2 to 0.2",
                    "d": "0.1 to 0.1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "0.8 to 0.8",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 43,
            "question": "The value of 3 51 mod 5 is ________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "6 to 6",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "2 to 2",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 44,
            "question": "Consider that 15 machines need to be connected in a LAN using 8-port Ethernet switches. Assume that these switches do not have any separate uplink ports. The minimum number of switches needed is__________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "6 to 6",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "3 to 3",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 45,
            "question": "What is the minimum number of 2-input NOR gates required to implement a 4-variable function expressed in sum-of-minterms form as f =  (0, 2, 5, 7, 8, 10, 13, 15)? Assume that all the inputs and their complements are available. Answer: _______________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "3 to 3",
                    "b": "5 to 5",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "3 to 3",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 46,
            "question": "Consider the following C program: \n    #include <stdio.h> \n    int main(){ \n    float sum = 0.0, j = 1.0, i = 2.0; \n    while (i/j > 0.0625){ \n    j = j + j; \n    sum = sum + i/j; \n    printf('%f\n', sum); \n    } \n    return 0; \n    } \n The number of times the variable sum will be printed, when the above program is executed, is _________________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "5 to 5",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "5 to 5",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 47,
            "question": "The value of 3 51 mod 5 is ________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "6 to 6",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "2 to 2",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 48,
            "question": "Consider the following C program: \n     #include <stdio.h> \n     int main() \n     { \n     int a[] = {2, 4, 6, 8, 10}; \n     int i, sum = 0, *b = a + 4; \n     for (i = 0; i < 5; i++) \n     sum = sum + (*b – i) – *(b – i); \n     printf ('%d\n', sum); \n     return 0; \n     } \n The output of the above C program is __________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "10 to 10",
                    "b": "13 to 13",
                    "c": "12 to 12",
                    "d": "11 to 11",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "10 to 10",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 49,
            "question": "In an RSA cryptosystem, the value of the public modulus parameter is 3007. If it is also known that φ() = 2880, where φ() denotes Euler’s Totient Function, then the prime factor of which is greater than 50 is ____________________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "96 to 96",
                    "b": "93 to 93",
                    "c": "97 to 97",
                    "d": "91 to 91",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "97 to 97",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 50,
            "question": " Consider the augmented grammar given below: \nS' → S \nS → 〈L〉 | id \nL → L,S | S \nLet I0 = CLOSURE ({[S' → •S]}). The number of items in the set GOTO (I0 , 〈 ) is: ________. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "5 to 5",
                    "b": "3 to 3",
                    "c": "2 to 2",
                    "d": "1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "5 to 5",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 51,
            "question": " Two numbers are chosen independently and uniformly at random from the set {1,2 , . . . , 13}. The probability (rounded off to 3 decimal places) that their 4-bit (unsigned) binary representations have the same most significant bit is ___________",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": " 0.499 to 0.500",
                    "b": " 0.502 to 0.502",
                    "c": " 0.502 to 0.504",
                    "d": " 1 to 1",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "0.502 to 0.504",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 52,
            "question": "20 An array of 25 distinct elements is to be sorted using quicksort. Assume that the pivot element is chosen uniformly at random. The probability that the pivot element gets placed in the worst possible location in the first round of partitioning (rounded off to 2 decimal places) is ________.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "0.08 to 0.08 ",
                    "b": "0.07 to 0.07",
                    "c": "0.06 to 0.06 ",
                    "d": "0.09 to 0.09",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "0.08 to 0.08",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 53,
            "question": "The police arrested four criminals – P, Q, R and S. The criminals knew each other. They made the following statements: \n P says “Q committed the crime.” \n Q says “S committed the crime.” \n R says “I did not do it.” \n S says “What Q said about me is false.” \nAssume only one of the arrested four committed the crime and only one of the statements made above is true. Who committed the crime? ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "P",
                    "b": "R",
                    "c": "S",
                    "d": "Q",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "R",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 54,
            "question": "Two cars start at the same time from the same location and go in the same direction. The speed of the first car is 50 km/h and the speed of the second car is 60 km/h. The number of  hours it takes for the distance between the two cars to be 20 km is ___. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1",
                    "b": "2",
                    "c": "3",
                    "d": "6",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "2 ",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 55,
            "question": "Ten friends  planned to share equally the cost of buying a gift for their teacher.When two of  them decided not to contribute, each of the other friends had to pay Rs 150 more. The cost of the gift was Rs. ____. ",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "666",
                    "b": "3000 ",
                    "c": "6000 ",
                    "d": "12000 ",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "6000",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },

    ]
}
var quizApp = function (quiz) {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
        this.currentque = cque;
        if (this.currentque < totalque) {
            $("#tque").html(totalque);
            $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
            $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
            $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
            $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
            $("#question-options").html("");
            for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
                if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
                    $("#question-options").append(
                        "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
                        "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
                        "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
                        quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
                        "</span></label>"
                    );
                }
            }
        }
        if (this.currentque <= 0) {
            $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
        }
        if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
            $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
            for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
                this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
            }
            return this.showResult(this.score);
        }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
        $("#result").addClass('result');
        $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
        for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
            var res;
            if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
                res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
            } else {
                res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
            }
            $("#result").append(
                '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
                '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
                '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
                '</div>'
            );
        }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
        var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
        option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
        option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
        option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
        if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
            if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
                quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
                quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
            }
        } else {
            quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
        }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
        this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
        this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
}
function startQuiz(quiz) {
    var jsq = new quizApp(quiz);
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
        jsq.displayQuiz(0);
        $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
            //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
            $(this).prop("checked", true);
            selectedopt = $(this).val();
        });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
        e.preventDefault();
        if (selectedopt) {
            jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
        }
        jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
        e.preventDefault();
        if (selectedopt) {
            jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
        }
        jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });
}
startQuiz(quiz1);
